My Son Wants to Become a Woman
(Questioner) My son recently
went off to college.
He suddenly declared that
he would become a woman.
I'm so shocked and confused,
(Questioner) I don't know what to do.
Hence I came to seek your thoughts.
Have an honest conversation with him.
Then you'll know if he's actually a woman
inside although physically a man,
or whether he's just
going through a phase.
People can't force themselves
to change their sexual orientation.
If he feels love towards men
and not towards women,
he shouldn't be living
with a woman, should he?
The society we now live in recognizes
the freedom of sexual preference.
It allows people of
all sexual orientations
to freely express their preference.
In the past, homosexuality
was heavily suppressed.
People had to go through
tremendous sufferings.
Nowadays we accept all for who they are.
In the past we discriminated people
for their skin color,
for their disabilities
and for their gender.
Nowadays we are all equal, are we not?
Sexual orientation is
the one last thing remaining.
Usually men like women, women like men
but it's not always the case.
(Sunim) Do you understand?
(Questioner) I do.
So once you confirm through examinations
that he truly is how is he claims to be,
you should accept him as is.
(Questioner) But I don't
want him to live that way.
Who doesn't?
(Questioner) I don't.
But it's not your life.
That's true. For now I've made a hospital
appointment to assess his sexual identity.
The results come out this Friday.
You're saying that if he insists,
I should let him be...
He's not insisting
because he has a choice.
He is who he is,
what can he do about that?
But I don't see any femininity in him.
It's not like he likes doing household
chores or dresses in a feminine way.
He actually likes guns.
He likes assembling things.
He likes games and guns.
Even now he likes taking apart guns
and reassembling them back.
And yet he now claims he wants to live
as a woman. It just seems far off.
You're thinking wrong.
Why should household
chores be for women?
Women usually prefer men
sexually, do they not?
In your case, you prefer men over women,
that is a sexual orientation
you're born with.
Liking guns has nothing to do with it.
Many women serve in the army these days.
Many women become mechanical engineers.
Many men are stay-at-home
dads, many are chefs.
Your way of thinking is
too old-fashioned.
(Questioner) Is it?
Sexual orientation has nothing to do
with occupations or hobbies.
It's a different concept altogether.
So consult a specialist doctor,
act accordingly.
It's natural for you
to be shocked as a mother.
In the past, parents and society have
suppressed different sexual orientations.
Hence those people experienced
enormous pain and struggle.
They had to live hidden lives
as if they were criminals
due to social stigma.
We now live in a much better era where
people express their identity freely.
And yet people are still condemned
for it nowadays, are they not?
I know a gay person, he ended up marrying
a woman to avoid other's judgement.
And yet his life was unhappy
living with a woman.
(Sunim) So he'd engage in extramarital
homosexual affairs.
(Sunim) The wife would
come to consult me.
So rather than putting
others through such pain,
it's better to consult a specialist
and follow his guidance.
It's not something you should
worry too much about.
In Korea, it's still considered a social
taboo, we keep quiet about it.
But in other countries,
people of all sexual orientations
become social public figures.
Many play a prominent role in arts.
Apart from their sexual orientation,
they are just like us.
They are good natured people.
They rarely commit crimes,
they are kind hearted, gentle
and detail oriented.
Hence many work in the art scene.
Now when kids are young,
kids of the same gender
may like each other.
This might be more of
a exploring phase, but if it's not
and you're born a certain way,
it can't be changed.
It's not something to worry about.
As a mother, you should rather listen
closely to your child's issues
and help him overcome them.
You shouldn't oppress him,
it's ultimately not your life to live.
(Questioner) But I'm still worried for
him, he's been living as a man.
Even so there's nothing you can do.
Had you known earlier,
it would have been easier.
Now that you know,
it's better late than never.
(Questioner) I understand,
thank you.
It's natural for it to come
as a shock to a mother.
But your child did nothing wrong.
He was born a certain way,
what is he supposed to do?
It's evident that there are cases
where the psychological state
and physical state don't match.
There are also those that are physically
born with both sexes within oneself,
there are others without a sex.
There are males, females,
hermaphrodites, intersexuals.
Do you understand?
(Questioner) But sunim...
In this case, your son isn't necessarily
feminine himself, but he prefers men.
In the past we denied it,
but we now know it's possible for people
to prefer someone of the same sex.
Now we know as a fact
that such cases do exist.
Previously, it would be taken
as god's punishment,
people would live in disgrace
as if they had done wrong.
In today's society, we accept everyone's
sexual preference for what they are.
What did president Obama
declare recently?
He said that he'd accept homosexual
marriages as a fundamental right.
He expressed his agreement to it.
Even if the institution is quite not there yet,
you as a parent should embrace
your child for who he is.
You shouldn't condemn him
in this day and age.
But do get a specialist's opinion on it.
You shouldn't take action
without his/her advice.
Do you understand?
(Questioner) Yes.
Will you worry about it or not?
(Questioner) It depends
on the test results.
I wholeheartedly understand
it's tough for you as a parent
to deal with a child of a minority.
But as a mother, you should
put his happiness first.
Do you understand?
(Questioner) Yes, I do.
For the sake of his happiness, discuss
with him more once the results are out.
(Questioner) Yes.
Don't be too shocked.
It's nothing in this day and age,
unlike 20 years back.
It would have been
a much bigger issue then.
Parents would have lost their mind,
they would've scolded
their children for it.
Now we know it can't be changed.
We all are born in this world
to live rightfully
as a human with dignity,
and to pursue happiness.
This we call human rights.
(Questioner) I understand,
thank you.
Sure.
(Applause)